<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason Bryer on Jason Bryer</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jason Bryer on Jason Bryer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Editable DataTables for Shiny Applications</title>
      <link>/post/2018-22-26-dtedit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-22-26-dtedit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rstudio.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt; recently updated &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.rstudio.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt; to allow for &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.rstudio.com/2018/03/29/dt-0-4/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;editable &lt;code&gt;DataTables&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Their implementations allows for editing cells direclty with in the &lt;code&gt;DataTable&lt;/code&gt; view. This is fine for many advanced applications, however, for many applications more fine tuned control of what the user can edit is necessary. For example, you may want to only allow a subset of columns to be editable. Or you want to view a subset of columns in a spreadsheet view but allow other columns to be editable. The &lt;code&gt;DTedit&lt;/code&gt; package takes the editing out of the table view and instead presents the user with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.rstudio.com/articles/modal-dialogs.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;modal dialog&lt;/a&gt; for editing table contents (see screenshot below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started, use the &lt;code&gt;devtools&lt;/code&gt; package to install the latest development version of &lt;code&gt;DTedit&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;devtools::install_github(&#39;jbryer/DTedit&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;dtedit_demo&lt;/code&gt; will run a sample &lt;code&gt;shiny&lt;/code&gt; app with to editable data tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;DTedit::dtedit_demo()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jbryer/DTedit/master/inst/screens/dtedit_books_edit.png&#34; alt=&#34;DTedit Screen Shot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started-with-dtedit&#34;&gt;Getting Started with &lt;code&gt;DTedit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download a simple shiny app using &lt;code&gt;DTedit&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jbryer/DTedit/blob/master/inst/template/app.R&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;from Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three steps to using &lt;code&gt;DTedit&lt;/code&gt; in your shiny application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-define-callback-function-for-inserting-updating-and-deleting-data&#34;&gt;1. Define callback function for inserting, updating, and deleting data.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: These callback functions assume that &lt;code&gt;mydata&lt;/code&gt; is already defined somewhere outside the callback functions. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jbryer/DTedit/blob/master/inst/template/app.R&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt; for the complete example using &lt;code&gt;data.frames&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jbryer/DTedit/tree/master/inst/shiny_demo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this demo&lt;/a&gt; for an example using &lt;code&gt;RSQLite&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;my.insert.callback &amp;lt;- function(data, row) {
	mydata &amp;lt;- rbind(data, mydata)
	return(mydata)
}

my.update.callback &amp;lt;- function(data, olddata, row) {
	mydata[row,] &amp;lt;- data[1,]
	return(mydata)
}

my.delete.callback &amp;lt;- function(data, row) {
	mydata &amp;lt;- mydata[-row,]
	return(mydata)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically these functions would interact with a database. As written here, the data would be lost between shiny sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-create-the-dtedit-object-within-your-server-function&#34;&gt;2. Create the &lt;code&gt;dtedit&lt;/code&gt; object within your &lt;code&gt;server&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;DTedit::dtedit(input, output,
	   name = &#39;mycontacts&#39;,
	   thedata = mydata,
	   edit.cols = c(&#39;name&#39;, &#39;email&#39;, &#39;useR&#39;, &#39;notes&#39;),
	   edit.label.cols = c(&#39;Name&#39;, &#39;Email Address&#39;, &#39;Are they an R user?&#39;, &#39;Additional notes&#39;),
	   input.types = c(notes=&#39;textAreaInput&#39;),
	   view.cols = c(&#39;name&#39;, &#39;email&#39;, &#39;useR&#39;),
	   callback.update = my.update.callback,
	   callback.insert = my.insert.callback,
	   callback.delete = my.delete.callback)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;input&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;output&lt;/code&gt; are passed from the &lt;code&gt;server&lt;/code&gt; function. The &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; parameter will define the name of the object available to the &lt;code&gt;uiOutput&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;thedata&lt;/code&gt; is a &lt;code&gt;data.frame&lt;/code&gt; for the initial view of the data table. This can be an empty (i.e. no rows) &lt;code&gt;data.frame&lt;/code&gt;. The structure of the &lt;code&gt;data.frame&lt;/code&gt; will define the inputs (e.g. &lt;code&gt;factor&lt;/code&gt;s will be drop down, &lt;code&gt;Date&lt;/code&gt; will use &lt;code&gt;dateInput&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;numeric&lt;/code&gt;s will use &lt;code&gt;numericInput&lt;/code&gt;, etc.). There are many other parameters to custom the behavior of &lt;code&gt;dtedit&lt;/code&gt;, see &lt;code&gt;?dtedit&lt;/code&gt; for the full list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-use-uioutput-in-your-ui-to-display-the-editable-data-table&#34;&gt;3. Use &lt;code&gt;uiOutput&lt;/code&gt; in your UI to display the editable data table.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; you will pass to &lt;code&gt;uiOutput&lt;/code&gt; is the name you passed to the &lt;code&gt;dtedit&lt;/code&gt; created on the server side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;uiOutput(&#39;mycontacts&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAACS</title>
      <link>/project/daacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/daacs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PBIS</title>
      <link>/project/pbis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pbis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Likert</title>
      <link>/project/likert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/likert/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Shiny</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-03-03-open_data_day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-03-03-open_data_day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be teaching a short Introduction to Shiny as part of the Open Data Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Data Day is a collection of local gatherings of open government advocates, developers, programmers, statisticians, and citizens who want to build things with and promote the use of open data through project hacking. The next Open Data Day is March 3, 2018. The event welcomes participants from all backgrounds, interests, and skill sets with a common enthusiasm for transparency. In addition to project hacking, participants can learn about some of the tools in the open data toolkit by joining in the training workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Event website: &lt;a href=&#34;http://opendataalbany.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://opendataalbany.org/&lt;/a&gt;
Please RSVP Here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://opendatadayalbany.splashthat.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://opendatadayalbany.splashthat.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSA</title>
      <link>/project/psa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/psa/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Predictive Modeling</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-01-22-intro_to_predictive_modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-01-22-intro_to_predictive_modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop will introduce the basic concepts and procedures for predictive modeling in R including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to evaluate the quality of predictive models using confusion matrices and ROC curves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classification and regression trees (CART methods)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensemble methods (e.g. random forests, boosting, bagging)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion of issues and limitations of &amp;ldquo;black box&amp;rdquo; predictive modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Propensity Score Analysis</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-03-28-intro_to_psa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-03-28-intro_to_psa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The use of propensity score methods (Rosenbaum &amp;amp; Rubin, 1983) for estimating causal effects in observational studies or certain kinds of quasi-experiments has been increasing in the social sciences (Thoemmes &amp;amp; Kim, 2011) and in medical research (Austin, 2008) in the last decade. Propensity score analysis (PSA) attempts to adjust selection bias that occurs due to the lack of randomization. Analysis is typically conducted in two phases where in phase I, the probability of placement in the treatment is estimated to identify matched pairs or clusters so that in phase II, comparisons on the dependent variable can be made between matched pairs or within clusters. R (R Core Team, 2012) is ideal for conducting PSA given its wide availability of the most current statistical methods vis-à-vis add-on packages as well as its superior graphics capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide a theoretical overview of propensity score methods as well as illustrations and discussion of PSA applications. Methods used in phase I of PSA (i.e. models or methods for estimating propensity scores) include logistic regression, classification trees, and matching. Discussions on appropriate comparisons and estimations of effect size and confidence intervals in phase II will also be covered. The use of graphics for diagnosing covariate balance as well as summarizing overall results will be emphasized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Of The Large Scale Diagnostic Assessments Of College Skills</title>
      <link>/talk/2017-nera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2017-nera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) is a technology-based, no-stakes
diagnostic assessment system on academic and non-academic skills, with fast, actionable feedback.
Development and piloting of these assessments at two online colleges is underway. Preliminary validity
and reliability evidence of these assessments are reported in this paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Bryer, Excelsior College; Fusun Sahin, American Institutes for Research; Heidi Andrade, Angela Lui,
Diana Akhmedjanova, &amp;amp; David Franklin, University at Albany, SUNY&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficacy of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Students on Multiple Success Indicators</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-aera-efficacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-aera-efficacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study is to examine the effects and predictive power of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) on student success. DAACS is a no-stakes, open-source, formative assessment tool designed to measure newly enrolled college students’ reading, writing, mathematics, and self-regulated learning (SRL) skills, and provide them with feedback and resources to enhance their functioning and success. A randomized control trial was performed at two online colleges (n = 17,687) to measure the effects in terms of academic achievement and credit acquisition. Predictive power of DAACS on student success were also examined. Results highlights the importance of using DAACS as a suite of assessments and supports, and not as isolated components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback on Writing for College Success: Machine Scoring of Essays on Self-Regulated Learning</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-sigwriting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-sigwriting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper describes an ongoing project in which on-demand writing is used as part of a diagnostic evaluation of newly admitted college students. The authors will present preliminary evidence of the validity and reliability of human and machine scored essays and the usefulness of the feedback provided to students on their writing and their self-regulated learning. The purpose of the project, the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS), is to develop a no-stakes diagnostic assessment designed to help students transition to college. Research suggests that mindset, self-regulation, and grit are predictors of college success (Duckworth, Peterson, Matthews, &amp;amp; Kelly, 2007; Zimmerman &amp;amp; Schunk, 2011). DAACS provides feedback to students about their strengths and weaknesses in mathematics, reading, and writing, as well as their self-regulated learning (SRL) skills, and links students to appropriate resources and support. For the writing assessment, students write an essay reflecting on the results of a survey about their self-regulated learning skills. In addition to encouraging students to reflect on their SRL, the writing assessment provides feedback about their writing and directs them towards relevant writing resources. Although this approach is similar to Directed Self-Placement (Gere et al., 2010), DAACS is not intended to be used for placement; rather, it helps students determine whether they need support as writers. The scoring rubric developed for this assessment includes five criteria: content, organization, paragraphs, sentences, and conventions. An open source, automated program called Lightside was trained with hundreds of essays scored by human raters. Preliminary results indicate acceptable agreement between human and machine scores, and high rates of student and advisor satisfaction. These results and implications for uses of machine scoring of essays will be presented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relationship Between Intraclass Correlation (ICC) and Percent Agreement</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-ncme-irrsim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-ncme-irrsim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inter-rater reliability (IRR) is a critical component of establishing the reliability of measures when more than one rater is necessary. There are numerous IRR statistics available to researchers including percent rater agreement, Cohen&amp;rsquo;s Kappa, and several types of intraclass correlations (ICC). Several methodologists suggest using ICC over percent rater agreement (Hallgren, 2012; Koo &amp;amp; Li, 2016; McGraw &amp;amp; Wong, 1996; Shrout &amp;amp; Fleiss, 1979). However, the literature provides little guidance on the interpretation of ICC results. This article explores the relationship between ICC and percent rater agreement using simulations. Results suggest that ICC and percent rater agreement are highly correlated ($R^2 &amp;gt; 0.9$) for most designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Placement Exams: The Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-innovations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-innovations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This session will introduce a new open source formative assessment developed as an alternative to tradition placement exams that measures self-regulated learning, reading, mathematics, and writing. Results from a pilot study conducted at two large online institutions will be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) addresses the issues with traditional placement exams and remediation programs by providing students with immediate, detailed, formative feedback. In addition to assessing students in reading, writing, and mathematics, DAACS also assesses non-academic areas such as academic self-regulation, metacognition, strategy use, motivation, self-efficacy, grit, and test anxiety. Once students complete a DAACS assessment, they are directed to open education resources (OERs) to address any potential gaps in their academic skills while emphasizing their strengths. Student results are used by Student Success Coaches to inform targeted interventions based upon student&amp;rsquo;s individual feedback report and performance. Additionally, these data contribute to the College&amp;rsquo;s predictive analytics efforts with a goal of increasing the accuracy of predicting &amp;ldquo;at-risk&amp;rdquo; students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This forum will introduce DAACS including the theoretical reasoning for this approach. Participants will have the opportunity to complete DAACS for themselves to review the assessments and feedback available to students (&lt;a href=&#34;https://demo.DAACS.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://demo.DAACS.net&lt;/a&gt;). An overview of training for Academic Advisors will also be provided. Results from a study conducted at two large online institutions will be provided which provide evidence of the psychometric qualities of the assessments and the impact on student success.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-dtl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-dtl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the issues of placement exams impact most less selective or open enrollment colleges, the efficacy of DAACS as an alternative to traditional placement exams was conducted at two large online distance education colleges: Excelsior College and Western Governors University. DAACS is an assessment framework that provides students with a formative view of their skills in self-regulation, reading, writing, and math. For administrators, DAACS provides valuable information to inform personalized interventions and more accurate risk modeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This session will cover to aspects of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS): Instrument development the efficacy study. Results suggest that DAACS is a valid and reliable assessment of self-regulated learning, reading, mathematics, and writing. We will discuss the development process and psychometric qualities of these assessments. Part two will cover the efficacy study being conducted at two online institutions (Western Governors University and Excelsior College). Specifically, a large randomized control trial is being conducted (n &amp;gt; 10,000) to address the two research questions above. Preliminary results suggest there is no statistical difference in student outcomes, but there is a statistically significant increase in the accuracy of models predicting term-to-term retention (~ 5%). The implications for the null result to question one and the planned changes to the intervention will be discussed. It should be noted that some research suggest that placement exams and remediation programs have a negative effect on student retention and therefore a null result could be viewed as an improvement. However, follow-up analyses of the prediction models reveal important interactions between self-regulation domains and academic measures that will inform modifications to the intervention, specifically vis-à-vis targeted interventions, or nudges, for both students and academic advisors/mentors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validity and Reliability of the DAACS Writing Assessment</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-ncme-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-ncme-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The DAACS system assesses incoming college students’ readiness in reading, writing, mathematics, and self-regulated learning. The purpose of this study is to examine validity and reliability evidence for the internal structure of the writing assessment. The evidence suggests that our conceptual framework holds for both human and machine scored essays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
